[Queen] Your first mission
will be to lead all the soldiers
here to capture my food.
I want you to capture
more of those highly
nutritious organisms for me.
[Colt] I shall.
[opening theme music playing]
[singer singing in Japanese]
[singer singing in English]
VERY X RAPID X REPRODUCTION
[narrator]
The Chimera Ants are insatiable carnivores
which are currently under the designated
quarantine level one.
Once these creatures have evolved
beyond two meters in length,
humans no longer stand a chance.
[farmer sighs]
Huh?
Huh.
[insects buzzing]
Hey, what the hell is that?
[farmer] Huh?
[farmers exclaim frightfully]
[Colt]
Target the fully grown ones!
They will provide the most nutrition.
Now go!
[farmer screams]
[grunts]
[all screaming]
[men screaming]
[shuddering]
[grunts]
[gasps]
[Kite] A Chimera Ant Queen
stays on the move
until she finds a site she likes.
During her search,
she'll produce more and more soldier Ants,
building her own personal army.
Once she's chosen a location,
she produces a swarm of construction Ants
to build her castle with incredible speed.
She will remain within
that fortress until her death.
Should a queen who has
reached two meters in height
develop a taste for human flesh,
no one is safe.
Entire towns and villages will go missing,
victims of the queen's limitless hunger.
Nothing so far.
I just finished checking out
the past six months,
and the largest group I could find
only numbered ten.
Hey, can we try looking
for missing people individually?
Don't be ridiculous.
You know how many
hundreds of thousands of people
go missing worldwide each year?
[Killua] We could still see which areas
have the highest concentrations, though.
Mmm, well… no good.
This data is two years old.
[Gon] Maybe we should start
by checking for sightings.
[Killua] Yeah,
seeing a two-meter-tall insect
would be a big deal.
[Spinner] Sure, that goes without saying,
but we tried that already.
We didn't turn up anything.
We might be getting
all worked up over nothing, guys.
Maybe so.
Bring up all the tidal data
from the day the arm was found.
[Spinner] It was discovered
right around here.
Now try going back to ten days ago.
[keyboard clacking]
Locate any currents that could
potentially have carried the arm
to that location in that period of time.
Wait. What do you mean?
I mean that we should consider
the possibility the arm was severed
after the Chimera Ant
washed up somewhere else.
I see.
Seems it could have come
from any of the Balsa Islands.
And unfortunately
that includes the Mitene Union.
Seriously?
Oh! Where the NGL Autonomous Region is.
Yes, and that's
not to mention East Gorteau.
No chance of getting information
out of those two countries.
What's the NGL?
NGL's an acronym
that stands for Neo-Green Life.
[Stick] It's a country founded by people
who reject modern technology,
choosing instead to live in nature.
[Spinner] Here it is.
[Spinner]
They primarily communicate by mail,
and primary travel is by horseback.
Anyone who brings technology
into the country could be executed.
Like back in '87, there was
a three-man television crew
that was caught trying
to enter the country
in order to get a story.
One was executed,
and two are still jailed.
99% of its 2.17 million population
belong to the NGL Party.
The rest are volunteers.
[Kite] Let's assume for now
that the Chimera Ant washed ashore there.
How would the NGL's citizenry react?
I doubt they'd do anything.
When a deadly epidemic
spread through the area,
they refused international medical aid,
because they preferred to let nature
run its grisly course instead.
Even if they tried to contact
the outside world,
it would be too late
by the time word arrived.
So if the arm
that was discovered did belong
to the Chimera Ant Queen,
then it's entirely possible
that she's already begun
constructing her nest.
[Colt] A contest?
[Alligator Ant]
Yeah, between you and me.
Just a friendly challenge
to see which one of us
can bring the Queen more humans to devour.
-What do you say, huh?
-[scoffs]
Hmm? You're running away?
Accept my challenge!
[Colt] What?
Are you ordering me around?
Tell me. Why should I follow
an order from you?
I only follow orders given to me
by the Queen herself.
Oh, give me a break.
You're just scared of losing.
See, my squad is comprised
of elite soldiers.
I can beat any squad
in this entire castle.
Hey, I know.
I should get the other
squad leaders in on this,
make it a group thing.
If we all compete against each other,
we're bound to capture more prey.
So that's the goal?
I see. I agree with your premise.
If we gather more prey,
the Queen will be quite pleased indeed.
Well, okay, then. That settles it.
However, the quality of the prey
matters as well.
It's very important to ensure
that the Queen eats
only highly nutritious humans.
That guy's such a stiff,
it's not even funny.
But that's what makes him so endearing.
He's as loyal
as he is dedicated to the cause.
I presume that the human
from which he was created
was also quite earnest.
[crying]
Oh.
Where are you going?
I told you to get some rest, didn't I?
I'll go bring her back.
Don't bother. It won't help.
But she's been going to the forest
every single morning
and spending her whole day searching.
That's right.
She'll probably collapse
from exhaustion soon.
But she still can't stop
looking for her missing children.
That's what it means to be a parent.
[farmer 1] How long has it been now?
How many days ago
did Kurt and Reina vanish?
[farmer 2] It's like the spirits
whisked them away.
-[children laughing]
-[boy] Yeah!
Huh?
Wow. Those bugs are big.
[Colt] It's an area we haven't raided yet.
-[girl screams]
-[gasps]
[grunts]
[gasps]
[sobs]
[man screams]
Mommy!
[farmer 1] It was them,
those awful monsters!
They must have been the ones
that stole your children from you!
[gasps]
[elder grunts]
[crowd murmuring]
Excellent. The Queen will be most pleased.
This will be more than sufficient,
I'm sure.
-[gunfire]
-[gasps]
[hostages screaming]
[gasps] What?
Exterminate the insects quickly.
That's Gyro's direct order.
Gyro? What is Gyro?
The name of our king, you fool!
Damn it.
[Spinner] Okay, I just bought us
tickets to the Mitene Union.
But in order for us to reach the NGL,
it looks like we'll
have to take an airship
to the neighboring Rokario Republic,
and then we can travel by land
the rest of the way.
Well, those nasty rumors
"ants" gonna help.
Just kidding. [laughs]
Nasty rumors?
Like what?
Have you heard of DD?
[Gon] Uh, no.
[Kite] It's a drug propagating rapidly
in urban areas worldwide.
It's derived from the Bira Tree,
which is native to the Mitene Union.
And not only are they
native to the region,
but they claim over 80%
of the world's Bira Trees
are located in the NGL.
Okay, so the nasty rumors are
that the NGL is manufacturing it?
They're still only rumors.
No one has been able
to prove it publicly yet.
The country is locked down tight.
When anybody tries
to get in and investigate,
they're instantly executed.
They are?
[Pokkle] He wasn't killed?
-Hmm?
-No.
If he had been captured trying to uncover
the NGL's secrets,
then there's a good chance
he would have been executed
like that TV crew man.
But this reporter wore a recording device.
Our goal was to intercept
the final message,
and that's how we did it.
When the message was played…
[reporter] M-Monsters! Gigantic bugs!
[static crackling]
Gigantic bugs, huh?
Mmm. So what do you think?
Hmm. I can't be sure
without knowing a lot more.
-[chuckles]
-[men] Huh?
I'll have to see for myself.
I mean, I am the only
Magical-Beast Hunter here.
That settles it.
I'll go get three tickets for the journey.
-[Ponzu] Make it four.
-[men] Huh?
[Pokkle] Ponzu?
I'm coming with you guys.
You can't! This is too dangerous!
You don't even have
a professional license yet,
and we're talking about
the NGL here, remember?
And that's why.
You're not allowed to bring technology
into the NGL, right,
so if they catch you
with any cell phones
or wireless communicators,
guaranteed you'll be
arrested on the spot.
All I'm saying is if there's any trouble,
you guys'll need me,
or rather, you'll need them.
[buzzing]
If you have a letter for someone,
they can carry it anywhere you like.
[chuckles]
I get it.
They'll sure come in handy.
[indistinct announcements]
It may be too late to ask this,
but are you sure you want to come along?
Of course.
You weren't kidding
about the "late" part, huh?
As you know, we have no idea
what the situation is inside the NGL.
There may very well be
a swarm of giant Chimera Ants
already hunting humans down.
And if that does indeed
turn out to be the case,
then my priority will be saving them.
So, be aware that I may
not be able to help you two.
If you're going to join us,
you must be able to protect yourselves.
Right. I got it.
We're okay.
And if it happens to be me
who finds himself in danger,
then leave me there.
Uh…
You got it?
[tense music playing]
[Alligator Ant] Hey,
that's a pretty good haul.
Well, it's less than half
of what my squadron delivered,
but it's okay.
[Colt] My focus was quality,
and I wasn't competing with you.
[scoffs] Whatever.
So anyway, did you hear?
That turtle guy's group ran into
a bit of human resistance.
You don't say.
[page turns]
Hmm. What you saw
were probably things called guns.
Guns?
To put it simply, it's a barrel
that launches small
metal projectiles, or bullets,
using the explosive force of gunpowder.
It's one of the most commonly
used human weapons.
I have no idea what you're talking about.
If you want to know more,
then read these books.
They're wonderful and filled
with quite useful information,
such as how humans think, behave,
and function as a society.
[Turtle Ant] Maybe you can answer
a question for me, then.
These humans, do they have armies, too?
Why do you ask?
Well, because what attacked us out there
was an army.
That much I know.
They belong to a military body
led by an authoritative figure,
much like us.
Oh, yes, and I have another question.
They mentioned something about a name?
A name? Hmm.
I can see why you're confused.
It's a human idea and one that
we do not make use of ourselves.
In terms you would understand…
It seems humans are capable
of more than we thought.
I was beginning to think
all they could do was cry and run away.
And why does that surprise you?
You and I are quite different
ourselves, are we not?
It's only natural that humans would have
unique traits as well.
Their blood, after all,
flows through all of our veins.
[tone ringing]
[Queen] Squadron leaders, assemble!
Squadron leaders, assemble!
The Queen is summoning us.
[Queen] Squadron leaders, assemble!
Do you get a headache
every time the Queen calls to us,
or am I the only one?
No, my ears start ringing like crazy
whenever I hear it.
A shame, really.
If only the Queen could talk like we do.
[Queen] I shall now begin preparation
for the birth of the King.
Every day from this day forward,
you will deliver me 50 humans.
[Chimera Ants] Yes, Majesty!
[Turtle Ant] Your Majesty,
may I ask a question?
[Queen] Yes. Speak.
Among the humans
are soldiers like ourselves, my Queen,
with weapons to use against us.
If I may make a suggestion,
we must fortify our defenses
in preparation for a potential attack.
We have already come up
with a few options.
Would you care to hear them?
[Queen] I will allow you
to decide your own course.
For now, I must focus entirely on my son.
[Turtle Ant gasps]
Thank you, Your Majesty.
But one more thing,
may we have your permission to have names?
[Queen] And what is a name?
[Turtle Ant] It's like a label, my queen,
one that can be used to identify
each of us individually.
[Queen] Fine. Do as you please.
[Turtle Ant] I am eternally grateful.
[Queen] Curious creatures.
They're assertive and desire things
called names to be distinct.
They place a high value on individualism,
yet strive with one another
for the good of the colony.
I suppose I'm just as peculiar
to find this change fascinating.
Perhaps, just perhaps,
I, too, have faint traces
of human blood within me.
Regardless, I cannot help
but feel great anticipation.
Yes. I can sense you already,
almost as if recalling
a memory from my own past.
I promise you this,
you shall stand at the pinnacle
of all species!
Names, amusing little things.
The three elite royal guards,
I shall come up
with a name for you myself.
[airship whirring]
[Killua] Well,
what did you just decide?
[Gon] You remember
what Kite said before we left,
that we should escape
without him if he's in danger?
[Killua] Yeah. He didn't make it
sound like it was a choice.
[Gon] Right.
And that's why neither one of us
felt comfortable saying anything.
But there's something
that I've been thinking about.
Do you really think Kite,
a guy Ging respects,
can ever actually be in that much danger?
You said before that Ging had a reason
for bringing Kite and me together.
So do you still think that?
Yeah.
Lately I've started
to think you're right.
I don't know the reason,
and maybe I never will,
but I can't give up.
And it doesn't matter
what's going on here.
I just don't want
to disappoint Ging, you know?
Or me. I couldn't forgive myself, either.
I won't run away.
That's what I've decided.
Damn it.
You had such a serious look on your face,
I was expecting something big,
but it's the same stuff as usual.
[Gon] Huh? I thought about it a lot.
I even ran a bunch
of simulations in my head.
[Killua] Think all you want,
you're still Gon.
If someone said you should abandon them,
there's no way you'd ever do it.
[Gon sighs]
You make it sound like I
wasted my time considering it.
Okay, then, so what about you?
Don't know.
I guess I'd just think about it
when the time comes.
Hold on. You mean you might run away?
Depends on what happens.
Look, I don't really do
these hypotheticals.
[Gon] Fine, but what if--
[Killua] Look, I already told you.
I don't know what I'd do, okay?
I never decide 'til it's time.
[narrator] And so, the airship,
along with the group
and all of its other passengers,
begins the journey
for the Mitene Union
still completely unaware
of the cruel fate
which lies in store for them.
[closing theme music playing]
[singer singing in Japanese]
[epic music playing]
[Gon] Next time, "No good NGL."
[Killua] Ready, go!
[Gon] It's probably not
in this coun… [sighs]
[Killua] And there's your outtake, folks.
[singer singing in Japanese]